creativebug.com 2018-10-23

# Creativebug - Craft Classes & Workshops - What will you make today?

Creativebug, LLC  
Privacy Policy

## Introduction

Welcome to the www.creativebug.com network of websites and applications. This Privacy Policy is intended to inform you of our policies and practices regarding our use and disclosure of the information that you submit to us, and the information that we collect from you through our web site and our applications, including mobile applications.

Whenever we use the words “we” or “us” or “Creativebug,” we are referring to Creativebug, LLC (doing business as Creativebug™), and to our affiliates and parent companies, including Jo-Ann Stores, LLC. Whenever we use the words “our web site,” we are referring to our applications and to [http://www.creativebug.com](http://www.creativebug.com/).

This Privacy Policy is divided into the following sections:

  1. Definitions
  2. Consent
  3. How We Collect Personal Information
  4. How We Use Personal Information
  5. Our Disclosure of Your Personal Information
  6. Advertising
  7. Social Network Widgets
  8. Testimonials and Affiliate Program
  9. How You Can Stop Receiving Communications
  10. Information From Children Under 13
  11. Links to Other Web Sites
  12. Security
  13. Your California Privacy Rights
  14. Questions about this Privacy Policy
  15. How to Access or Correct Personal Information or Opt Out of Marketing and Advertising
  16. Revisions to the Privacy Policy

## 1\. Definitions

“De-identified Information” means information that is no longer associated with you, or linked to your Personal Information (as defined below). De-identified Information does not reference the identities of individual persons.

“Cookies” are small pieces of information that a web site, including our web site, sends to your computer or to your mobile device while you are viewing a web site. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that are placed onto your computer’s hard drive. Cookies identify your computer so that we can recognize you the next time you visit us. Cookies help us remember your preferences and collect technical information about your use of the Services. We use both session Cookies (which expire after you close your web browser) and persistent Cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them) to provide you with a more personalized and interactive experience on our web site. Persistent Cookies can be removed by following your Internet browser help file directions. If you choose to disable Cookies, some areas of our web site may not work properly.

An “Internet protocol address” or “IP Address” is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. In some cases, your IP Address stays the same from browser session to browser session, but if you use a consumer internet service provider, your IP Address probably varies from session to session. We track IP Addresses in conjunction with session Cookies to analyze our web page traffic flow and also to identify the location of the computer.

“Offerings” means our Products and Services.

“Personal Information” is information about you that is linked to you as an individual, such as your name, postal address, email address, phone number, credit card number and expiration date, account username and log-in password to our web site. Personal Information does not include technical information such as unique device identifiers, randomly assigned unique identifiers in cookies, mobile device name, or IP addresses. 

As detailed below, we and our business partners obtain and keep Personal Information when you send us an email, order or purchase Offerings on our web site, sign up for one of our programs, or communicate with us.

“Products” means any tangible products available on our web site.

“Services” means the various services available on our web site.

## 2\. Consent

Our web site is maintained in the state of California in the United States, and by submitting your Personal Information to us, either through our web site, or by other means, you are agreeing to the collection and storage in the United States of your Personal Information.

When you submit Personal Information and De-identified Information to us, either through our web site, or by other avenues, it means that you have agreed to this Privacy Policy, and that you expressly consent to the use of your Personal Information in the United States, according to this Privacy Policy.

Please note that your Personal Information may be used by Creativebug in the country where it was collected, as well as in the United States, where laws regarding the use of Personal Information may be less strict than the laws in your country.

## 3\. How We Collect Personal Information

The Personal Information that we gather from you helps us learn about our customers and our potential customers. We use this Personal Information to better tailor the features, performance and support of our Offerings and web site, and to offer you additional information, if you have consented to receive it.

We (or our business partners, on our behalf) collect and keep Personal Information that you submit to us voluntarily to our web site, through our applications, by purchasing Offerings or when enrolling in classes, or through third party websites or emails, in the following ways:

  * When you register and set up an account on our web site, we collect your name, your account username, password, email address, and payment information either Paypal or credit card information (number, type of card [Visa, MasterCard, etc.] and expiration date). We may also collect your postal address (shipping address and billing address) and telephone number(s) when applicable.
  * When you order or purchase an Offering, we collect your name, your account username, password, email address, and payment information either Paypal or credit card information (number, type of card [Visa, MasterCard, etc.] and expiration date). We may also collect your postal address (shipping address and billing address) and telephone number(s) when applicable, all which may be shared with a third-party payment service.
  * We collect additional information such as your location, demographics, preferences and interests.
  * We maintain a record of your purchases on our web site and the classes you have watched.
  * If you post materials on our web site with your Personal Information, we may post that Personal Information, and we may link your postings with other personal information (e.g., your account with us) for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.
  * When you sign up to receive emails, we collect your email address and may also collect your postal address when applicable. We also ask for information, such as hobbies and interests, to provide you with relevant offers. 
  * When you order or purchase Offerings on our web site for delivery to other people, we collect your name, the recipient’s name, your email address, the recipient’s email address, your personalized email message to the recipient, your billing address, the recipient’s postal (shipping) email or address, your telephone number(s), the recipient’s telephone number(s), and your Paypal or credit card information (number, type of card [Visa, MasterCard, etc.] and expiration date), which may be shared with a third-party payment service.
  * When you contact us by email, we collect your name, email address, and any other information contained in the email that you send us.
  * When you enter a sweepstakes, we collect your name, postal address, country, email address and any other information required to enter the sweepstakes.
  * When we receive Personal Information about you from other sources, we will add this information to the information we have already collected from you.
  * When you call, email or chat with our customer service, we may collect all or some of the following: name, email address, postal address (shipping address and billing address), telephone number(s), Paypal or credit card information (number, type of card [Visa, MasterCard, etc.] and expiration date, order number, merchandise to be purchased, other information that you provide during the interaction.

On our web site, we (or our business partners, on our behalf) also collect other information from you automatically, through the use of technology, without you taking steps to submit that information, whenever you use our website for any purpose (shopping, submitting a request to customer service, researching projects and merchandise, etc.), in the following ways:

  * As you navigate our web site, we collect information including your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times, operating system, other device identification information, and navigational and clickstream data that shows what pages are visited and how long various features are used.
  * We also use Cookies (described in Section 1, “Definitions”), pixels, and navigational data like uniform resource locators (URL) to collect information regarding the date and time of your visit, the products for which you searched and viewed, and the other resources on our web site that you used or visited. In addition, our web site and emails from Creativebug may contain code or pixels that cause Cookies to be placed in, or read or modified from, a user’s or email recipient’s browser cache. If you are logged in, we may associate this information with your account.
  * We also engage third parties to monitor the usage of the Services and our web site.
  * When you access our web site from mobile devices (such as smart phones or tablets), we collect information including access times, the operating system, the products for which you searched and viewed, and the other resources on our web site that you used or visited.
  * We may use and associate historical data with a computer or device as part of our efforts to prevent fraud, credit card fraud, or other illegal activity.

## 4\. How We Use Personal Information

We may use any of the information described in this Privacy Policy for any or all of the following purposes, without limitation:

  * to establish user accounts;
  * to provide the Offerings, including supporting and completing the transactions or other requested activity;
  * to communicate with you regarding your subscription or account;
  * to provide you with information you have requested, news and updates, and information about Offerings;
  * to customize and personalize content to you;
  * to administer and run our web site;
  * to help identify you if you lose your password and to help you find information on our web site;
  * to facilitate payment to or by us;
  * to send commercial email or marketing messages to you; and
  * to comply with legal requirements.

Personal Information that we collect from a particular browser or device, including a mobile device, may be used with another computer or device that we have linked to the original browser or device, including a mobile device, on which such Personal Information was collected.

We may create De-identified Information from Personal Information by excluding information (such as your name) that makes the information personally identifiable to you. We may use this De-identified Information to analyze request patterns and usage patterns so that we may enhance our products and services. As this De-identified Information does not identify you, we use and disclose De-identified Information to third parties at our discretion. 

If you provide feedback on any of our Offerings, we may use your feedback for any purpose. We will collect any information contained in your communication and will treat the Personal Information in the communication in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## 5\. Our Disclosure of Your Personal Information

We share your personal information with our affiliates, partners and third-party independent contractors (unaffiliated service providers), for purposes that include: (1) hosting our web site; (2) approving and enabling your use of our web site and use and purchase of our Offerings, and performing other functions on our behalf; (3) providing you with Offerings; and (4) tracking information generated through the Site. You expressly consent to the sharing of your Personal Information in the United States with our third party service providers.

Our partners and third-party independent contractors are bound under contract not to use or share your personal information for unauthorized purposes.

We generally restrict access to Personal Information to our employees and agents with a need to know in order to perform their respective duties. Our “agents” may include third-party service providers.

We reserve the right to share some or all of your Personal Information with our subsidiaries, joint ventures, and other companies in the United States under the common control of Jo-Ann (collectively, “Affiliates”), for the purposes described in this policy. We will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy.

Regardless of any choices you make regarding your Personal Information, we may disclose your Personal Information if we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with laws or to respond to subpoenas or other judicial orders served on us, (b) to protect and defend the rights or property of Creativebug, Affiliates or third parties; (c) to enforce the Terms and Conditions of Use of our web site and this Privacy Policy; (d) to prevent imminent harm; or (e) if we find that your actions on our web site violate any laws, or any of our usage guidelines.

To provide offers that are of interest to you, we may allow other companies to place advertisements and other technology on our web site. As a result of your visit to our web site, advertisement server companies may collect information such as your domain type, your IP address, and clickstream information.

We may also use and disclose Personal Information for fraud detection and prevention. Personal Information and device identification information may be combined with information from other sources and used by us, or by a third party retained by us, to help detect and prevent fraud, credit card fraud, or other illegal or illegitimate activity. All or part of your Personal Information or device identification information may be kept by us or kept by the third parties involved in fraud detection, and used in future fraud prevention efforts. Information that is believed to be fraudulent may be shared with other retailers, banks, and law enforcement to help prevent illegal activity.

We may use and disclose Personal Information in connection with a contemplated reorganization or an actual reorganization of our business, in connection with financing, a sale or other transaction involving the disposal of all or part of our business or assets, including for the purpose of permitting the due diligence required to decide whether to proceed with a transaction. If the sale occurs, the purchaser will be entitled to use and disclose the Personal Information collected by us, and the purchaser will assume the rights and obligations regarding your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy. We may transfer part or all of your Personal Information in the case of a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, or other sale of all or a portion of our assets or stock.

## 6\. Advertising

We use “interest-based” advertisements, also known as “online behavioral advertising.” Online behavioral advertising is advertising that is directed to you based, at least in part, on your Internet browsing behavior. We may share Personal Information with the third parties that conduct advertising campaigns for us. Third parties and their affiliates collect certain information as a result of their “tags” being on our website. The information that they collect includes the name (URL) of the web pages you view while on our site, your IP address, time of visit, information about your browser software, information about your device, and randomly-assigned identifiers stored in Cookies, which they use to target and serve advertising to you. We will use all this information to serve advertising to you. 

In connection with online behavioral advertising, some third parties involved in advertising operations may maintain their own proprietary consumer databases that allow them to personally identify or track website visitors. Other third parties have proprietary technologies to determine what additional devices you may use, and they may then display advertisements on those additional devices.

Do-Not-Track is a public-private initiative that has developed a “flag” or signal that an internet user may activate in the user’s browser software to notify websites that the user does not wish to be “tracked” by third parties as defined by the initiative. For more information, visit <http://www.w3.org/>. As explained below, some web sites, including our web site, will ignore a “do-not-track” signal.

As required by Section 22575 of the California Business and Professions Code, the following disclosure is made to California residents and to residents of other states: Our web site does not alter its behavior or change its services when it receives a “do-not-track” flag or signal from your browser. As described in Section 3, “How We Collect Personal Information,” we use Cookies and other tools to collect information about you when you visit our web site to better tailor the features, performance and support of our products, services, stores, and web site. After you leave our web site, we do not track your online activity on other web sites, but third parties (and their affiliates) may track your online activity to offer you advertisements.

You can make decisions about your privacy and the ads you receive. You can control whether companies serve you on-line behavioral advertising by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance website and using its opt-out: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>. The DAA opt-out requires that cookies not be blocked in your browser. As explained in section 11, we do not represent or warrant that the actions taken on other web sites will be effective.

For mobile devices and applications, you can visit the following website to opt-out of behavioral advertising: <http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices>. As explained in section 11, we do not represent or warrant that the actions taken on other web sites will be effective.

As an alternative to the DAA opt-out, you can also elect to block all Cookies from first parties (such as those from our website) and Cookies from third parties (such as advertisers) by using the cookie blocking options built into your browser software. For example, in Internet Explorer 9, you can block both first-party and third-party cookies by selecting those options at _Tools/Internet Options/Privacy/Settings-Advanced/Override Automatic Cookie Handling_. Also, if you are using Firefox 25, you can “uncheck” _Accept All Cookies_ under Firefox _Preferences/Privacy-Use Custom Settings For History/Accept Cookies from Sites_. If you block Cookies, some parts of our website may not function correctly. We do not represent or warrant that these actions will be effective to accomplish their purpose.

We may use a third party service provider to manage our product review system. When you submit product reviews on our website, our third party service provider may place Cookies on your browser and offer advertising to you. For more information on how this provider uses your information, please visit this link: <http://go.bazaarvoice.com/848PGD1740001EG001ipQ00>

## 7\. Social Network Widgets

Our website includes social network or other third-party plug-ins and widgets that may provide information to their associated social networks or third-parties about your interactions with our web pages that you visit, even if you do not click on or otherwise interact with the plug-in or widget. Information is transmitted from your browser and may include an identifier assigned by the social network or third party, information about your browser type, operating system, device type, IP address, and the URL of the web page where the plug-in or widget appears. If you use social network tools or visit social networking sites, you should read their privacy disclosures, to learn what information they collect, use, and share. Information you decide to share with a third-party platform is subject to that third party’s privacy policy and information practices. Any information we receive from such third-party platforms from which you choose to connect, link or access the Services is subject to this Privacy Policy.

## 8\. Testimonials and Affiliate Program

We may post your testimonial on our web site and in marketing materials used on other web sites, in email, social media, or other marketing assets along with your name. If you want your testimonial removed, please contact us at <https://creativebughelp.zendesk.com/hc/en-us>.

### Affiliate Program

If you participate in our Affiliate Program, we will collect your name, website name, website URL, email address and affiliate program payment preferences (including bank account number and routing number, bank account name, PayPal account email address, billing address and other financial information). We use this information to enable your participation in the Affiliate Program and to make payments related to it.

## 9\. How You Can Stop Receiving Communications

When you receive advertisements, direct mail, and other promotional communications from us, including email, you will have the opportunity to “opt-out” by following the “unsubscribe“ instructions in the email you receive, or by contacting us directly. If you have submitted your email address to “unsubscribe,” please note that you may continue to receive emails for a time while our system updates your request. You also may use the “Contact Us” page on our website. 

## 10\. Information from Children Under 13

We do not intentionally gather Personal Information about visitors to our web site who are under the age of 13. If you learn that your child under age 13 has provided our web site with his/her Personal Information, please contact us and we will attempt to disable that information.

## 11\. Links to Other Web Sites

Our web site may provide link(s) to another web site or internet location. Some features of the Services may allow you to connect, link or access the Services via a third-party platform (e.g., a social network such as Facebook or Twitter). We provide these links merely for your convenience, and we do not endorse the other web site or location, its contents, or any goods or services available through that web site. We have no control over, do not review, and are not responsible for these other web sites, their content, or any goods or services available through the web sites. Our Privacy Policy does not apply to these other web sites. The privacy policies of the operators of the web sites will be applicable when you access their web sites through the links provided on our web site. Please visit each third-party platform’s privacy policy to better understand the applicable data collection practices and the permission controls available.

## 12\. Security 

Our web site has implemented electronic means of protecting your Personal Information. Even though we have taken steps to ensure that your Personal Information is not accessed, used, or disclosed by unauthorized persons, you should know that we cannot fully eliminate security risks associated with Personal Information.

You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your password. Do not share it with others. Creativebug will not ask you for your password. If you need a new user name or password, we may require you to follow certain security procedures (such as providing us with certain Personal Information or correctly answering security questions). If satisfied with your answers, we will generate a new user name and password automatically through our computers and send it to your email. You may never use another’s account without permission. When creating your account, you must provide accurate and complete information. You are solely responsible for the activity that occurs on your account. You agree to notify Creativebug immediately of any suspected or known breach of security or unauthorized use of your account. Although Creativebug will not be liable for your losses caused by any unauthorized use of your account, you may be liable for the losses of Creativebug or others due to such unauthorized use.

## 13\. Your California Privacy Rights

Under Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, residents of California have the right to request from a business, with whom the California resident has an established business relationship, certain information with respect to the types of personal information the business shares with third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes, and the identities of the third parties with whom the business has shared such information during the immediately preceding calendar year. To exercise your rights, you may make one request each year by emailing us at legal@joann.com with “Request for California Privacy Information” on the subject line and in the body of your message. Be sure to provide in the request sufficient information to properly identify yourself.

## 14\. Questions About this Privacy Policy

If you have questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:

Creativebug, LLC  
c/o Jo-Ann Stores, LLC  
Attn: Senior Legal Counsel  
5555 Darrow Road  
Hudson, OH 44236

Email to: [legal@joann.com](mailto:legal@joann.com)

## 15\. How to Access or Correct Personal Information, or Opt Out from Marketing and Advertising

If you would like to modify your personal information on our database, please log onto your account by clicking the “Login” link on the website. Registered users may modify their privacy settings, and may correct, modify and update their personal information at any time by logging into their account and making their desired changes. Registered users may also “un-register” or ask that your information be deleted, in which case we will remove you from our list of registered users, but we reserve the right to retain personal information until we determine there is no potential need for it. We may also retain personal information to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems and enforce our Terms and Conditions of Use. In addition, it may not be technologically possible or feasible to remove each record of the information you have provided to us. A copy of your personal information may exist in a non-erasable format that will be difficult or impossible for us to locate. Information may also persist in backup copies.

Where you make use of the social networking and online features of our web site to share information (such as submitting comments or questions, posting photos or other materials, or submitting an entry to a contest or poll), it may not be possible or practical for us to remove the communications and materials and any associated personal information, and those communications, materials, and information may persist, including on third-party computers and other media. 

Except in limited circumstances governed by law, you may obtain access to and have your Personal Information in our records corrected. In addition, upon request, you may have your Personal Information opted-out of future marketing and advertising efforts by us. A request for access, correction or opt-out must be made in writing to the address provided in Section 14. 

Back to top

## 16\. Privacy Policy Updates

This Privacy Policy is subject to revision and changes at any time in our sole discretion. If you object to any changes, you must stop doing business with us, including business on our web site. Your continued use of our web site, will indicate your acknowledgment of the changes and agreement to be bound by the provisions of this Privacy Policy, as revised.

This policy was last revised in August 2017
